In this video, I'm going to show you how
I ordered a Meta Ads account when it is
running instant forms. If you're curious
about auditing an account that's running
landing pages,
I have another video that does exactly
that, but this one is specifically about
instant forms. My name is Gavin Winner.
I'm a top-rated freelancer, and I help
businesses specifically with their paid
ad campaigns, their sales funnels, and
their automations. I have an ad account
open right now, and you can see this one
is focused on instant forms. You can see
that by the results column there.
And the way I look at instant forms, it
is a funnel. Everything is a funnel when
it comes to paid ads. Even though
everything is happening still on Meta,
they're not having to leave the
platform, we still treat this like a
funnel. And I'm going to talk you
through how I analyze that, and also
that dictates why I have the columns
that I have.
If you want to get these columns as I
talk through them, all you got to do is
just click columns, you go to custom,
you add the columns from customize
columns, and then you save it as a
preset. That's what I do. When it comes
to ads, I think about it as a funnel.
The first step of the funnel is someone
sees the ad, then the only goal of the
ad is to get them to click through or
take the next step, which in this case
is to click through to the instant form,
and then the next step is completing the
instant form. The first step, as I said,
is the impressions. Are people seeing
the ad, and then are they clicking? So,
we obviously have our impressions and
our reach. Our reach is how many unique
people saw the ad, so that's why our
frequency is at about two.
But again, now the first step is is the
ad doing the thing that we want it to
do, which is to get them to click
through to the instant form.
In this case, we use link clicks cuz
they're not clicking off the platform.
In that case, we would be using outbound
clicks, which you will see in the video
that I ordered a landing page funnel.
But in this case, it's just link clicks,
and therefore we're looking at CTR link
click uh through rate. In this case, the
link click-through rate is pretty low,
and I'm going to talk you through how I
would analyze that in this case.
And then, the next step we have is
results. Very simple is how many people
are completing the form. So, you can
obviously do a rough calculation in your
mind of Okay, we have 221 link clicks,
and we have 59 results. So, our
conversion rate is about 20-ish percent
or so, maybe 25%. Not bad when you think
about it.
As I mentioned before, um and I will
have another video about this, is the
quality with instant forms, if you're
not using any of the conditional logic,
which is essentially qualifying
questions, the quality is going to be a
bit a little bit lower, so you do want
to be aware of that that even though we
have a 25% conversion rate,
approximately, we're going to need to do
a good bit of follow-up. We're going to
need to do a good bit of bit of
nurturing there, and also qualifying to
make sure they're like good quality
leads.
In this case, what I would have also
done,
if we were running this type of funnel,
is if we were say the next step was to
book get them to book in a call,
which you can do on the thank you page
for the instant form, you could say,
"If you want to book a time right now,
just click the CTA." And you can take
them to book a form page. Then, we can
also still push that information back,
whichever tool we're using, for example,
HighLevel, I work a lot with that. Then,
we would also add the appointment
scheduled column, and also the cost per
appointment. So, you can start to have
everything right in front of you without
having to into HighLevel or any of your
CRM or do any other calculations.
Now, what if something isn't performing?
Our first bottleneck is potentially is
the ad just not generating enough
click-throughs. Are people seeing the
ad, and they're just thinking, "I don't
care. This isn't for me."
And that's the first potential situation
is simply the creative and the the copy
is just not interesting enough. They're
seeing the image, they're seeing a
video, and it's not getting them to
stop. It's not um calling out the
specific person. The offer that's being
spoken about just isn't interesting
enough. So, if our CTR is too low,
like in this case, it already is pretty
low. I I should have refreshed the ads
in this case, but we were still getting
enough leads that it wasn't that big of
an issue. But, we would potentially want
to look at the quality of the leads that
we're getting and say, "Could we change
the messaging on the ads? We like Can
you do more creatives, more targeted,
try different creative angles in the
primary text,
etc." Now, let's say we had the link
clicks to results was very low. Let's
say it was like
5% or 10% on a lead form, an instant
form, which is crazy low cuz you can see
it can be as high as 25% in this case.
Then I'd be asking, "Are we asking too
many questions? Are we asking confusing
questions?
Uh we could be having very strong
qualifies, which isn't necessarily a bad
thing as long as the next step
of whether it's appointment scheduled or
converted into a sale or whatever it is,
we see a very high conversion rate
there. Then it's potentially not too
much of an issue if you're qualifying
very, very hard in your instant form if
that conversion rate is very high. So,
there's a lot of variables here that you
are balancing, but this is how I
approach it. This is my thinking of as I
said, this is all a funnel, and you're
just going step by step top to bottom,
and you're thinking, "Okay,
our numbers look good in this range. If
not, what's potentially the issue here?
Is it the creative? Is it the messaging?
Um with instant forms, are we asking too
many questions? Are we asking too
difficult questions? Are we qualifying
too hard, and now we're just not getting
enough leads, and our cost is way too
high?"
So, this is how I approach it when I am
auditing and reviewing a ad account. If
you want to get a free audit or if you
want help running your Meta ads, you can
then just find a link in the
description, and you can click that and
you can book in a time with me. If you
found this video helpful, the next one
that just popped up on the screen,
YouTube thinks you're also going to find
helpful and you can just click on that
and take a look.